Guide to the Lee Family Papers, 1754-1836
Department of Special Collections
Lee Family Papers,
1754-1836
Special Collections M0220
Lee Family
3.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1971, 1975, and 1978.
Biographical Note
Harcourt, Simon, 1st Earl Harcourt, 1714-1777
1735, May 9 Lord of bedchamber to George II.
1749, Dec. 1 Viscount Harcourt of Nuneham-Courtney and Earl Harcourt of Stanton Harcourt.
1751, Apr. gov. to young Prince of Wales (George III).
1761, July 3 ambassador extraordinary and minister plenipotentiary to Mecklenburg-Strelitz to demand hand of Princess Charlotte for the young king.
1761, Sept. 10 master of horse to the queen.
1763, Apr. 21 lord chamberlain of the queen's household.
1768, Nov. 4 ambassador ex. etc. to Paris.
1772, Oct. 9 lord - lt. of Ireland dif. sec. = John Blaquiere.
1775 vice-treasurer.
1735 m. Rebecca Le Bas of Pipewell Abbey d. 1765. George Simon, 2nd Earl d. 1809. William, 3rd Earl Elizabeth, d. 1811 m. Sir Wm. Lee of Hartwell. Anne
Harcourt, William, 3rd Earl Harcourt, 1743-1830, field marshall.
1759 ensign w/ troop 16th Lt. Dragoons Harcourt's Black Hourse.
1762 aide de camp to Lord Albemarle of Havanna.
1768 Lt.Col. 16th Lt.Dragoons.
1768-72 M.P. for Oxford.
1776 America, captured Charles Lee king's aide de camp
1782 Major general, purchase St. Leonard's Hall
1793 lt. gen.
1794-95 command of army til spring '95.
1796 gen. & gov. Royal Military College, Great Marlow 9 yrs.
1778 m. Mary, widow of Thomas Lockhart & d. of Rev. W. Danby. no children
William Lee Antonie, s. of William Lee d. 1778, g. s. of Sir Wm. Lee, lord chief justice. His sister married John Fiott.
Sir William Lee 3rd, Baronet Hartwell d. 1799, July 6. Devoted himself to improvement of Hartwell, rebuilt parish church; distinguished by his benevolent attentions to the poor and having studied the sciences of medicine was their gratuitous physician.
1763 m. Lady Elizabeth Harcourt.
William Lee, 1764-1801, Feb. 7. lt.col. 16th Lt. Dragoons.
George Lee, 1767-1825 or 1827, rector of Hartwell and vicar of Stone. m. by S. Harcourt July 9, 1867.
Scope and Content
2850 pp. in all, comprising the collected correspondence of Sir William Lee, fourth Baronet of Hartwell, Buckinghamshire, (b. 1764 - d. 1801) and other members of his family.
This collection of correspondence documents the career of an English army officer during part of the Napoleonic Wars, near the close of the eighteenth century.
The first letters were dated in the early 1770's when William Lee was a student at Harrow. Most of these letters are from Lee's father, Sir William Lee, third Baronet.
The next large group of letters are from Lee's relatives, the Harcourts including Simon Harcourt, father of Lee's mother and the first Earl Harcourt. Simon's letters are all addressed to his son-in-law, William Lee, third Baronet. His letters contain intelligent comments -- with interesting details -- upon affairs of court and upon the political scene.
Lee entered the 16th Light Dragoons as a cornet and later obtained the rank of Lieutenant-colonel. A short time after, Lee went with the Dragoons to the Continent (1793) to assist in the English campaigns against the French. From this period are copies of his own letters, letters of his friends in the army and letters from his father and Lady Elizabeth Lee, his mother. These letters offer an intimate picture of this unsuccessful phase of the English campaign against France.
Lee's own letters are important less for what they tell us about Lee himself than for what they say about English army life and about the politics of soldiership during this period when the reputation of George III's army was at a low ebb.
In addition to the letters, there are numerous official documents which further describe the activities of the 16th Light Dragoons in England, the Netherlands and France.
CHRONOLOGY
apparently also spent some time in Berlin in 1788 and/or 1789.
William Lee, 4th Baronet of Hartwell, 1764-1801.
1764, [Jan.?] born son of Wm. Lee, 3rd Baronet, & Elizabeth Harcourt Lee.
1776, July - 1781, June at Harrow &/or other school except holidays.
1781, [Aug.?] - [1784 or 85?] St. John's College, Cambridge.
1785, [July?] - 1791, Feb. Cornet, 16th (Queen's) Light Dragoons
1785, July - Aug. at Maidstone, England
1785, Nov. - 1786, Apr. at Canterbury
1786, Feb. 2 at London
1786, June - Sept. at Hartwell Estate near Aylesbury, England on leave
1786, Sept. 27 in London, on way abroad
1786, Nov. - 1788, Apr. Strasbourg, Germany, military study, etc.
1788,* May, July, Sept-Nov. Brunswick, Germany
[1788, May 18 Paris?]
1788, June 12 Magdebourg, Germany
[1788, Oct. 6, 10 Vienna?]
1788, Dec. - 1789, Feb. Vienna
[1789, Mar. 2 Strasbourg or Chalons-sur-Marne, France?]
[1789, Mar. 13 Vienna?]
1789, Apr. Croydon, England
1789, May - June London
1789, July 9 Bedford Coffee House
1789, July - Sept. Lewes, England
1789, Sept. 12 - Nov. Chichester, England
1789, Oct. 3 London
1789, Nov. 12 Hastings, England
1789, Dec. 29 St. Leonard's near Windsor (Country home of Gen. Harcourt)
1790, Jan. - Apr. 5 Chichester
1790, Apr. 23 [Guilford or Guildford?], England
1790, May 14 - 22 Epsom
1790, June 2 Tunbridge (to go to Hartwell for a month), England
1790, July [14?] - Sept. Maidstone
1790, Sept. 29 - Dec. Hartwell
1790, Oct. 17 London
1790, Dec. 28 Barnet, [or Chipping Barnet], England
1791, Jan. - Feb. Hartwell
1791, Feb. - 1793, [Apr.?] Lieutenant, 16th Light Dragoons
1791, Mar. 21 - Apr. 23 Canterbury
1791, May 12 London
1791, May 30 - Nov. Thetford, England
1791, Dec. 4 - 7 Newmarket, England
[1791, Dec. 10 London]
1791, Dec. 17 Norwich, England
1791, Dec. 31 - 1792, May Thetford
1792, Jan. 12 Leighton [-Buzzard], England
1792, [Mar.23], May 17,18, June 5 London
1792, June - July Hartwell
1792, Aug. 10 London
1792, Nov. 6 Dover
1792, Nov. 16 London
1792, Nov. 17 - 24 Hartwell
1792, Dec. Barnet
1793, Jan. 2 - 7 Barnet
1793, Jan. 9 [Hartwell?]
1793, Jan. 10 Newport Pagnell, England
1793, Jan. 24 London - to recruit at Leicester & Coventry
1793, Feb. 4 Leicester, England
1793, Feb. 9, 11 Sturbridge, England
1793, Feb. 15 [London], England
1793, Feb. 26 Coventry, England
1793, Mar. 19 Birmingham, England
1793, Mar. 27 London - ordered overseas
1793, April London
1793, Apr. 18 NP. embarkation orders - Lt. Lee assigned to Betsey
1793, [Apr.?] - 1794, Sept. Captain, 16th Light Dragoons
1793, May Ostend, Belgium (West Flanders)
1793, June - Sept. [Continent] Flanders, etc.
1793, Oct. 6 - 13 [Continent]
1793, Oct. 14 Camp at [Lysoing]
1793, Oct. 18 - Nov. 2 Tournay, Belgium
1793, Dec. 15 St. Mawr [or St. Maur, France?]
1794, Jan. 27 Outposts of Belleghem, Belgium, West Flanders
1794, Feb. 5 - 11 Audeuarde, Belgium, East Flanders
1794, Feb. 22 [Tournai?]
1794, Mar. 23 Courbourg
1794, Apr. 1 [St. Amand?], [Belgium]
1794, May 2 Ghent, Belgium, East Flanders
1794, May 9 - 12 London
1794, May 14 - [30?] Hartwell
1794, June 3 [London?]
1794, July 10 - Sept. 20 Flanders
1794, July 29 - commands 16th Lt. Dragoons on Continent
1794, Sept.- Major, 16th Light Dragoons
1794, Sept. 20 actions of 16th
1794, Oct. [8] [Zoelment]
1794, Oct. 14 Arnhem, Netherlands
1794, Oct. 30 - Nov. 24 Continent
1794, Dec. 3 [Hetteson?]
1795, Jan. Continent, Holland 16th
1795, Feb. 9 march to Rheine, Prussia
1795, Feb. 12 Rheine to Elte & Saerbeck
1795, Feb. 21 Rheine to Schaepen & Hofsten
1795, Mar. 2 Hofsten to Bokels & Apeldorn [Apeldoorn, Netherlands
1795, Mar. 7 a retreat
1795, Mar. 13 Apeldorn [Apeldoorn]
1795, Mar. 17 Continent, detachment of 16th to embark
1795, Mar. 20 Continent, Laurie's Brigade.
1795, Mar. 22 NP. march
1795, April Continent
1795, May Germany - [Bummersstede?], Oldenburg
1795, June Continent
1795, July Continent - Lunzen
1795, Aug. Continent - Lunzen - 9th
1795, Sept. Continent - 18 & 29 [Woltersdroff or Wulinstoy]
1795, Sept. 26 [Leeste?]
1795, Oct. Germany - [? Wolkersdorf, Austria Wollersdroff, Wolensdorff, Woltersdross Wulinstorf]
1795, Nov. 1 Continent, [Dowerdon?]
1795, Nov. 9 cavalry ordered to England
1795, Nov. 12 Hastede [Germany]
1795, Nov. 22 Malndorff
1795, Nov. 24 Scharmebeck
1795, Dec. 1 to march to Stade
1795, Dec. 2 [Hambergen]
1795, Dec. 3 - 8 embarkation orders, etc.
1795, Dec. 4 - 7 Stade, Prussia
1795, Dec. 6, 7 [Twielerfett?]
1796, Feb. 4 on board Prince of Wales returning from Continent
1796, Feb. 21] 29 Blackheath, England
1796, Mar. 1 St. Albans [commanding detachment]
1796, Mar. 3 problems with Emigrant Corps; C: Harcourt
1796, Mar. 4 re: India House, monopoly, shipping
1796, Mar. 11 St. Albans or Hampstead - Gwyn to postpone journey
1796, Mar. 15 St. Albans
1796, Mar. 19 politics, Wm. Lee Antonie in parliament. -on Thames, England
[1796? Mar. 23 Henley, Col.?]
1796, Mar. 29 re: Gwyn
1796, Mar. [London?]
1796, Apr. 8 - 16 Henley
1796, Apr. 18 - 30 Newbury. England Dunn court martial, Perry business, Francis Dana (29th)
1796, Apr. 21 Newbury, eve of resigning from command of foreign division, outline of career
1796, Apr. 23 Newbury &/or 20 Vere St.
1796, May 11 - 29 Newbury. Dunn & Rowse
1796, May 30 Hungerford England Dunn & Rowse
1796, June 1 [Newbury?]
1796, June 6 - 17 Panton Sq., London
1796, June 9 inoculating at Aylesbury
1796, June 12 Lee plans to leave Regt. & join Cathcart
1796, June 19 Richmond. England McKowan court martial
1796, July 2 Lee granted leave
1796, July 4, 5 Oxford
1796, July 9 - 27 Carnarvon, Wales
1796, July 17 Pitt etc. planning campaign
1796, Aug. 3 - 5 Carnarvon, Wales
1796, Aug. 18 Weymouth, England
1796, Aug. 20 Dorchester, England
1796, Aug. 28 Weymouth
1796, Sept. 4 Haymarket, London
1796, Sept. 10 Weymouth
1796, Sept. 14 Camp near Dorchester
1796, Sept. 23 Weymouth
1796, Sept. 28 Dorchester. Lee can't purchase Lt. Col'cy, wants to go with Cathcart to Portugal.
1796, Sept. 30 Reading. scarcity of wheat is over
1796, Oct. 2 - [29] Henley
1796, Oct. 12, 13 [Reading?]
1796, Oct. 22 Henley. promise of visit from Republicans (invasion), defenses, Portugal affair (Cathcart) given up.
1796, Oct. 28 [Marlow?] or Henley. march to Wycombe
1796, Nov. 14 Henley
1796, Nov. 19 [Reading?] a troop ordered to Bensington
1796, Nov. 20 [Nuneham?]
1796, Nov. 22 - [29] Henley
1796, Dec. 1 - 30 Henley. problems of promotion, finances, and the Vassars
[1796] Marlbro & Newbury & NP. re: Rowse, Le Marchant's book on sword exercise, Harcourt's orders.
1797, Jan. 10 - 19 Henley. difficulties with Vassar
1797, Jan. 12 mention of Directory in France
1797, Jan. 28 Reading. troops to be removed during fair
1797, Feb. 1 Henley or Thames
1797, Feb. 3 Henley
1797, Feb. 7 High [Wycombe]. rumored French invasion
1797, Feb. 13 - 18 Reading
1797, Feb 22 Reading or Henley, England
1797, Feb. 24 Henley
1797, Feb. 27 invasion rumors
1797, Mar. 3 Henley. invasion rumors
1797, Mar. 4 Reading. news of Jervis' success against Spanish fleet.
1797, Mar. 5 - 7 Hampstead
1797, Mar. [8] Beaconsfield
1797, Mar 10 Hampstead
1797, Mar 17 Reading
1797, Mar 22 - 28 Beaconsfield. Hompesch affair
1797, Mar 30 Henley
1797, Apr 3 Maidenhead
1797, Apr. 7 - 10 Beaconsfield. Hompesch affair
1797, Apr. 16 Hartwell. Lee's predicted promotion
1797, Apr. 17 - Lt. Col. 16th Light Dragoons - approved May 13, announced June 22, 23
1797, May 5 - 26 Beaconsfield
1797, May 13 promotion approved
1797, June 7 - 26 Beaconsfield
1797, June 22 - 23 announcement of promotion
1797, July 2 - 29 Maidenhead. Hoare & Palmer case
1797, Aug. 5 Guildford or Henley
1797, Aug. 7 Guildford
1797, Aug. 20 Chipping Wycombe. or High Wycombe Field Days at Dorchester
1797, Sept 20 - 29 Guildford
1797, Nov. 3 - 30 Guildford
1797, Dec. 7 Guilford
1798, Jan. 5 Uxbridge. Lee declines civil appointment
1798, Jan. 16 - 30 Guildford
1798, Feb. 1 - 6 Guildford
1798, Feb 8 [Webbes?] or Guildford
1798, Feb 12 London
1798, Feb. 15 - 26 Guildford
1798, Mar 3 - 18 Guildford
1798, Mar. 21 [London?]
1798, Mar. 25 - 31 Guildford
1798, Apr. 2 - 30 Guildford, England
1798, May 13 & 17 Guildford
1798, June 5 - 29 Guildford
1798, July 9 [Windsor]
1798, July 11 - 18 Guildford
1798, Aug. 5 - 17 Windsor
1798, Sept. 12 - 26 Windsor
1798, Sept. 21 re: India Co. service
1798, Oct 22 - 26 Windsor
1798, Nov. 13 [Hartwell?]
1798, Nov. 22 - 29 Windsor
1798, Nov. 29 shops closed for Thanksgiving
1798, Dec. 8 - 25 Windsor
1798, Dec. 24 re: Dragoons in Portugal need horses
1798, Dec. 29 [London?]
1798, Dec. __ report of patrol from Cornhill & plan in case of attack
1799, Jan. 3 - 9 Windsor
1799, Jan. 11 Hounslow Barracks, [near? Windsor]
1799, Jan. 13 - 22 Windsor
1799, Jan. 25 Old Windsor
1799, Jan. 30 Windsor
1799, Feb. 2,3 Hounslow Barracks
1799, Feb. 4 - 16 Windsor or Old Windsor
1799, Feb. 20 Hounslow
1799, Feb 23 - 28 Windsor or Old Windsor - District belonging to the Palace... privelege from arrests
1799, Mar. 2 - 5 Windsor or Old Windsor
1799, Mar. 6 Hounslow. Sarah Warwick acquitted
1799, Mar. 7 - 27 Windsor
1799, Mar 22 London in consternation over high treason against king & royal family.
1799, Apr. 9 Windsor
1799, Apr. 13 Salisbury. re: Hompesch, Santo Domingo, etc.
1799, Apr. 20 Old Windsor
1799, Apr. 23 Windsor
1799, Apr. 29 [Duke of York] approves Lee's study with Gen. [Janisse?]
1799, May 10 - 13 London
1799, May 14 [London] Hanover Square
1799, May 16 [London] Maddox St.
1799, May 17 - 25 Windsor; 18th - murder plan at Hounslow
1799, May 28 High Wycombe
1799, May 29 Hampton Court, England
1799, June 1 Windsor re: Jamaica, negotiation with [Tousaint]
1799, June 4 [High Wycombe]
1799, June 7 Hartwell
1799, June 13 Staines, England
1799, June 21, 22 Windsor
1799, June 23 Hampton Court,
1799, June 29 Windsor or [Sunninghell Wells?] instructing corps belonging to Speaker of House of Commons
1799, July 3 Windsor Camp
1799, July [6] death of Lee's father - Lee becomes IVth Baronet of Hartwell
1799, July 10 Windsor
1799, Aug. 2 Swinly Camp
1799, Aug. 18 Windsor or near
1799, Aug. 22 - 25 London
1799, Aug. 28 [Nuneham]
1799, Aug. 30 Hartwell
1799, Sept. 3 - 25 Hartwell
1799, Sept. 26 [Hounslow Barracks?]
1799, Sept. 30 Hartwell
1799, Nov. 2 - 9 Hartwell
1799, Nov. 9 new Lord Mayor's Carriage was drawn by the mob into the city today
1799, Nov. 12 - 21 Hartwell
1799, Nov. 20, 21 demands Lee return to regiment
1799, Nov. 23, 24 Windsor
1799, Dec. 2 - 16 Windsor
1799, Dec. 23 - 25 Hartwell
1800, Jan. Hartwell
1800, Feb. 8, 9 Windsor
1800, Feb. 17 - 20 London
1800, Feb. 20 Lee has transferred from 16th Light Dragoons to 25th.
1800, Mar. Hartwell - preparations for voyage to India
1800, Apr. 7 - 10 London - Portland Place. arrangements for journey
1800, Apr. 26 - 29 Hartwell. packing, etc.
1800, May 13 Portsmouth. England ready to embark
1800, May 17, 25 on board Indiaman Rockingham
1800, July on board Indiaman Rockingham
1800, July 18 on board, below equator, fleet dividing, mail to go via Rio
1800, Nov. - Dec. on board... dispute between crew & passengers
1800, Dec. 3 on board... Lee ill
1800, Dec. 28 Madras, India
1801, Feb. [7] Madras, India; Fort George, death of Lee
Container List
- ORIGINAL LETTERS AND DOCUMENTS
  - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1. N.D.,N. P. [Sir Ralph Abercromby/ie] to Major Lee. NP. Unsigned instructions re: obtaining forage.
    - 2. N.D.,N. P. William Aitken & John Fotheringham A.D.S. Memorial re: H.M.S. Vestal ramming transport Snow Jason and account of damage.
    - 3. N.D.,N. P. J. Aldridge by (H. Sudberg) to Major Lee. Henley. L. re: payment for horses.
    - 4. 1788, May 24.Brunswick, James [Alwort] to M. Lee. Magdebourg. A.L.S. sending belongings, dog's bad eye.
    - 5. 1796, Mar. 1.Adj. General's Office Jeff Amherst to Officer commanding a Detachment of the 16th Regt. of Light Dragoons [Wm. Lee?] N.P., A.L.S. request for weekly returns.
    - 6. 1794, Oct. [8].[B--] John Anderson to Maj. Lee. [Zoelment?] A.L.S. Sir Robert Laurie wants a squadron from the 16th at [Nyssigen?] with others to be put under command of Lt. Col. Churchill.
    - 7. 1799, Mar. 2.N.P. Wm. Andrews to Col. Lee. Old Windsor. A.L.S. question of paternity; Stone, Marlow, Bancroft.
    - 8. 1799, Mar. 6.N.P. Wm. Andrews to Col. Lee. Hounslow. A.L.S. Sarah Warwick acquitted of murdering her child, Marlow.
    - 9. N.D.St. James Square, [London]. Thos. Anson to [Wm.] Lee. N.P. A.L.S. personal, social, Vienna Club, ball for German ladies.
    - 10. N.D.St. James Square [London]. T. Anson to [Wm. Lee] N.P. A.L.S. horse, Vienna ball.
    - 11. 1794, Jan. 6.N.P. T. Anson to [Wm.] Lee on Foreign Service A.L.S. A!s brother Geo. with Army in West Indies. A.N. [Lee] to Smollett. incomplete, personal.
    - 12. 1795, Feb. 9.[Oldenstaal] R. Anstruther to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. march route to Rhine.
    - 13. [1797], Mar. 26.[Colworth] W. Lee Antonie to to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. Baron Hompesch.
    - 14. 1781, May 5.[Harrow?] Tomas Applewhaite to W. Lee [Portland Place, London] A.L.S. speaking of Harrow. accident in West Indies.
    - 15. N.D.,N.P. Thomas Applewhaite to [W.] Lee. N.P. A.L.S. Harrow, school friends, etc.
    - 16. 1795, June 22.Durham. Clement Archer to Maj. Lee on the Continent. A.L.S.
      re: promotion, Lord Paget, St. Leger, Le Marchant.
    - 17. 1796, Oct. 2.Marlow. Clement Archer to Maj. Lee [Henley] A.L.S. military returns, etc.
    - 18. 1797, Mar. 15.Gt. Marlow. Clement Archer to Maj. Lee. Reading. A.L.S. military, horse.
    - 19. 1799, Oct. 12.Hounslow's Barracks. Clement Archer to Lt. Col. Lee. Hartwell near Aylesbury. A.L.S.
    - 20. N.D.Marlow. Clement Archer to Maj. Lee. Henley. A.L.S. horse of Tomlinson's Troop.
    - 21. N.D.[Deptford] C. Archer to Maj. Lee. Hamstead. A.L.S.
    - 22. N.D.Hounslow Barracks. C. Archer to Col. Lee. Windsor. A.L.S. need money, deserters.
    - 23. N.D., Aug. 27.Hounslow Barracks. C. Archer to Col. Lee. Windsor. A.L.S.
    - 24. N.D.[Barnet] Clement Archer to Maj. Lee. Hampstead, A.L.S. debt at Marlow.
    - 25. N.D.N.P. [Clement?] Archer. Account for recruiting duty.
    - 26. 1759, Feb. 4.Coopersale. Mary Archer to [Sir Wm. Lee III] N.P. A.L.S. Ann Davis dismissed, honesty suspect.
    - 27. 1790, Oct. 22.Dover. Wm. Archer to Lee. N.P. A.L.S. re: Invalids.
    - 28. 1790, Nov. 1.Dover. Wm. Archer to Lee N.P. A.L.S.
    - 29. 1790, Nov. 13.Dover. Wm. Archer to Capt. Wm. Lee. Hartwell. A.L.S.
    - 30. 1796, Sept. 4.Abbey. Wm. Archer to Maj. Wm. Lee. Weymouth. A.L.S. purchase of rank.
    - 31. N.D., June 23.Norwich. Wm. Archer to Capt. Wm. Lee. Maidstone. A.L.S. personal, Sir Robert.
    - 32. 1798, Feb. 10.Leeds. -- Armstrong to Maj. Gen. Fox. Chatham Barracks. A.L.S. a Richard Steele of 16th Lt. Dragoons.
    - 33. [1788?], Dec. 1.Dresden. C. Ashley to M. Lee, Vienna. A.L.S. no carnival at Vienna, Princess Antoine, the Electress.
    - 34. 1788, Dec. 27.Dresden. C. Ashley to M. Lee, Vienna. A.L.S. prodigious frost and snow, Sir R. Murray Keith.
    - 35. 1789, Jan. 11.Dresden. C. Ashley to M. Lee. Vienna. A.L.S. social life, Elbe frozen.
    - 36. 1797, Dec. 20.Aylesbury. Postmaster of Aylesbury to Mr. Freeling. N.P. Extr. of L. Sam'l. Dudley impersonating Lt. Col. Lee.
    - 37. 1798, Feb. 18.Hampton Court Barracks. Willm. Ayllott to Lt. Col. Lee. Guildford. A.L.S. re: an AWOL.
  - AFFLECK 1795-1800 & N.D. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1. 1795, July 7.Cooper. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. orders and instructions.
    - 2. 1795, Sept. 18.Cooper J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. [Woltersdross?] A.L.S.
    - 3. 1796, Mar. 4.[London]. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S.
    - 4. 1796, Apr. 23.N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. 20 Vere St. A.L.S. Gen. Harcourt.
    - 5. 1796, Oct. 8,Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. Henley. A.L.S. supplies.
    - 6. 1796, Nov. 2.N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. frag.?
    - 7. 1796, Nov. [20].Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. horse shoes.
    - 8. 1796, Nov. 25.Maidenhead. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. Henley. A.L.S.
    - 9. 1796, Nov. [29].Finchley. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. Henley. A.L.S.
    - 10. 1796, [Dec.] 8.Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. court martial.
    - 11. 1797, Jan. 23.N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. leave.
    - 12. 1797, May 14.Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. court martial, Capt. Archer.
    - 13. 1797, May 15.Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. Beaconsfield. A.L.S.
    - 14. (There is no number 14.)
    - 15. 1797, June 2.Reading. J. Affleck to [King George] N.P. L.S. thanks for King's bounty-pay increase, thanks to Duke of York, attempt to withdraw the Soldiers from their duty.
    - 16. 1797, June 7.[Baringstoke] J.Affleck to Maj. Lee. Beaconsfield. A.L.S. deserters, supplies.
    - 17. 1797, June 17.Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. purchasing.
    - 18. 1797, June 19.Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. Beaconsfield, A.L.S.
    - 19. 1797, June 23.N.P. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee. N.P. A.L.S., horses, congratulations on promotion.
    - 20. 1797, June 26.N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee. Beaconsfield. A.L.S. horses, review and practice.
    - 21. 1797, July 2.Reading. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee, Maidenhead. A.L.S. Lees court martial, etc.
    - 22. 1797, July 19.Reading. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. to meet at General Harcourt's.
    - 23. 1798, May 2.Reading. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. forgery?, court martials.
    - 24. 1798, Dec. 9.[Bath?] J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee. Windsor. A.L.S. bad soldiers, annual inspection.
    - 25. 1799, Jan. 22.[Hounslow] Barracks. J. Affleck to [Lt.] Col. [Lee]. N.P. A.L.S.
    - 26. 1799, Feb. 12Hounslow Barracks. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee, Windsor. A.L.S. instructions to be followed during A's absence.
    - 27. 1799, Feb. 12.Hounslow Barracks. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee. Old Windsor, A.L.S.
    - 28. 1799, June 24.N.P. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee. N. P. A.L.S. Robert Smith bearer.
    - 29. 1799, June 25.[Vere] Street. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee. N.P. A.L.S. Capt. Archer.
    - 30. 1799, June 29.[Vere] Street. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Lee, Windsor. A.L.S. instructing a Corps belonging to the Speaker of the House of Commons.
    - 31. 1799, Oct. [12?]N.P. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Sir Wm. Lee, Bart., Windsor. A.L.S. misconduct in forage dept.
    - 32. 1799, Oct. 28.N.P. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Sir Wm. Lee, Bart., Windsor. A.L.S.
    - 33. 1799, Nov. [20].N. P. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Sir Wm. Lee, Bart., N.P. A.L.S. return to regiment.
    - 34. 1799, Nov. 21.Windsor. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Sir Wm. Lee, Bart., N.P. repeat more strongly #33.
    - 35. 1800, Jan. 12.St. Leonard. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Sir Wm. Lee, Bart., Hartwell. A.L.S.
    - 36. 1800, May 13.N.P. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Sir Wm. Lee, Bart., Portsmouth. A.L.S. bon voyage, Lee going to India.
    - 37. 1800, May 17.Canterbury. J. Affleck to Lt. Col. Sir Wm. Lee, Bart., Rockingham Indiaman. A.L.S. advises Lee what to take to India.
    - 38. N.D. May 12.Wimpole St. J. Affleck to Mons. Lee Strasbourg. A.L.S. Advises Lee on his studies.
    - 39. N.D. [1795?],N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. [Lee], N.P. A.L.S. supplies, breeches.
    - 40. N.D., June 21,N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. [Lee], Beaconsfield. A.L.S. court martial. [damaged, part of text missing.]
    - 41. N.D.N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee, Beaconsfield, A.L.S. armourer, court martial of West.
    - 42. N.D.,Reading, J. Affleck to Maj. Lee, Beaconsfield. A.L.S. pay increase, gratitude to King.
    - 43. N.D., May 16.Reading. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee, Beaconsfield. A.L.S. breeches.
    - 44. N.D.,N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee, Beaconsfield. A.L.S. subsistence.
    - 45. N.D., May 31.N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee, Beaconsfield, to be forwarded from Maidenhead immediately. A.L.S. Troops excused from parade to drink the King's health.
    - 46. N.D.,N.P. J. Affleck to Maj. Lee, N.P. A.L.S. Tudor, Lee to be given court martial(?), thin horses, establish hospital.
    - 47. N.D., Oct. 29.Reading, J. Affleck to Maj. [Lee] N.P. A.L.S. to send men to Tunbridge Wells.